So there was deep concern about how we looked if we were oppressing Black people explicitly.
I see.
Yeah.
See, that's a context I've never, ever had anyone present.
The optics were a part of it.
Yes.
Derrick Bell calls it interest convergence.
He used to say, he used to write that the only time Black people have made advancement in this country is when it was in the larger interest.
Certainly during the period of the civil rights movement, he's absolutely right about that.
President Eisenhower, who famously sent the 102nd Airborne to Little Rock High School to protect the Little Rock Nine and to see to it that they were able to enter the school and go to school that year and the following year, was a segregationist.
He was furious with the push to integrate schools, but he was deeply concerned about our position in the world.